Festival Accompanying Chapter
Part Three
The Beginning of the End
saa, wasuremashou sono mirai ga
Come, let us forget about the future...
Planning
Takeshi Oikawa
Akihiro Kawamura
Akihiro Yuasa
Original Work ・ Original Story/Supervision
Ryukishi07/07th Expansion
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni"
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai"
mata chinurarete yuku nante
...ending up stained in blood again.
Series Composition
Toshifumi Kawase
Character Design
Overall Animation Supervisor
Kyuuta Sakai
Art Director
Chikako Shibata
Color Design
Shinji Matsumoto
namanurui kaze toguro wo maitara
If the soft wind coils up...
Camera Director
Masayuki Kawaguchi
Editing
Masahiro Matsumura
Music
Kenji Kawai
Sound Director
Hozumi Gouda
sore ga tabun aizu
...that is probably a sign.
nukedashitette
Break free.
Opening Theme
"Naraku no Hana"
(Flower in Hell)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Eiko Shimamiya
Tomoyuki Nakazawa
Takeshi Ozaki
kanashisugiru unmei kara
From your heart-wrenching fate.
Music Producer
Music Production
Akira Yoshikawa
Frontier Works
anata wa naraku no hana ja nai
You are not a flower in hell.
Producers
Mika Nomura
Hiroyuki Oomori
Takeshi Okamura
sonna basho de sakanaide
Don't blossom in such a place.
Animation Producer
Animation Production
Kouji Iijima
Studio Deen
sakanaide
Don't blossom there.
karametorarete ikanaide
Don't get entangled.
oto mo naku tobikau toki no kakera
Fragments of time flutter about without a sound.
Kai
Hi
ni
ra
ku
Koro
gu
no
shi
Na
Kai
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
Director
Chiaki Kon
（男性）
そんなこと聞いてねえっつってんだ
We don't give a shit about that!
[Hinamizawa Dam Construction Project Clarification Meeting]
We want to know who gave you permission to build a dam!
（男性）
誰の断りがあって ダムなんか
造ろうと言いだしたかと聞いてんだ
（役人）でっ ですから先ほどから
申し上げておりますとおり…
L-Like we told you earlier...
（男性）
言い訳など聞いちゃおらんが！
We don't want excuses!
いつ計画を中止するか
聞いとるんじゃい！
We wanna know when the hell this project is gonna be canned!
（役人）しかしですねえ…
But you see...
（男性）
引っ込まんか　木っ端役人が
東京の建設大臣 連れてこい！
I've had enough of you petty officials!
Bring in the Minister of Construction from Tokyo!
（お魎(りょう)）静かにせんね
Be quiet.
（お魎）
とにかく この計画は認められん
Anyway, I can't approve of this project.
さっさと東京に帰って
そう伝えんしゃい
Tell your superiors to get their asses back to Tokyo.
This is the consensus of the village.
これが村の総意じゃにね
（村人たち）そうじゃー！
（役人たち）ハア…
Don't be stupid!
（北条(ほうじょう)）やかましい！
（北条）
それは おんどれの都合やんね
勝手に総意に せんといてえな
That's just to your own benefit!
Don't just declare it as being the consensus.
（男性）おうおう　てめえら
Hey, you assholes!
お魎さんと知ってて
その口 利いとるんかいな
Do you have any idea who you're talking to!?
上等きっちゃあ
You've got guts!
アア？　名乗らんかい　おう！
Who the hell are you?
Shut the fuck up!
やかあしい！
園崎(そのざき)が なんぼのもんじゃ？
わしゃ北条じゃ
I don't give a shit about the Sonozakis.
I'm Houjou!
（北条）
腰巾着は引っ込んどらんか ええ！
Back off you chump, I'm talking to her!
There are plenty of Hinamizawans that are piss poor, you hear!
いいんか！
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)には貧乏人も大勢おる
お前んとこみたいに―
Not all of us own huge patches of land in the mountains like you!
山に畑 うなるほど持っとる
地主とは わけが違う
わしゃあ あの国の補償金で
十分 満足しとった
I was more than satisfied with the government's compensation!
（北条）仕事も町の公営住宅も
手配してくれるっちゅうし―
They even arranged a job and public housing for me in the city!
なーんも不足は なかったんや
I had nothing to complain!
それを おんどれが
全部 台なしにしおったんや
But then you had to come in and ruin everything.
When the fuck did you become our representative!?
大体いつから おどれ
わしらの代表になったんじゃ！
Houjou...
（お魎）北条の…
ようも抜かした
この裏切りもんが！
How dare you say that, you damn traitor!
Why don't you get the hell out of the village then!?
おう 出ていったらあ
Yeah, I will!
もちろん それに見合う銭は
お前が払うんじゃろうなあ!?
Of course, after you cough up the cash I was entitled to!
What did you say!?
（男性）北条の言うとおりじゃ
It's like Houjou says!
（男性）立ち退いてもいいと
思ってる住人もいるんだ！
There are plenty of residents who want to get out of this place!
（男性）
御三家は俺たちを巻き込むなあ！
The three houses should keep their asses out of our business!
今 抜かしたのは誰じゃい!?
Who the hell said that!?
（男性）立ち退きも権利じゃい！
We have the right to leave this place!
Don't interfere with our rights!
（男性）
勝手に人の権利に干渉するなや！
Exactly!
そういうことじゃ
園崎のクソババアは引っ込んどれえ
Why don't you get out, old Sonozaki hag!
よう抜かしたわ…
Now you've done it.
よう抜かしたわ　北条の
Now you've done it, Houjou.
I haven't been this pissed in a long time.
この園崎お魎　ひっさびさに
頭に血 上ってきよったわ
きっちり けじめ
取らしてもらうかんな
I'm going to have you pay for this.
Better watch your back!
あんじょう楽しみに待っとれや！
ぶっ殺したるわ…
前ん出ろ　クソババア！
I'll kill you.
Stand up, you filthy hag!
（男性）
何 抜かしよるがあ　北条…
What did you say, Houjou!
（北条）雑魚は すっこんじょれ…
（男性）アタタタ…
Stay the hell out of this!
うんにゃー
（北条）ンエエ…
（男性）アアッ…
死ねや　北条！
（北条）ンッ…
Die, Houjou!
じゃかあしい…
（男性）エエッ
（男性）こんガキがあ！
You asshole!
（警官）やめなさい！
Stop it!
（役人）ごっ ご静粛に
皆さん　落ち着いて…　わああ…
K-Keep it civil!
Calm down, everyone!
（羽入(はにゅう)）みんなが
真っ赤な怒りに染まっていく
People are getting tainted red with anger.
I couldn't do anything to stop it back then...
すべては あの時に
止めることのできなかったボクは…
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
ごめんなさい…
I'm sorry...
Manager!
（悟史(さとし)）監督！　監督！
（入江(いりえ)）悟史君…
Satoshi-kun!?
ハッ…
（沙都子(さとこ)の息遣い）
（入江）沙都子ちゃん!?
Satoko-chan!
ハア…　やれやれ
（ドアが閉まる音）
Oh boy...
（鷹野(たかの)）
容体は落ち着いたようですわね
Looks like she's calmed down a bit.
Yes, somehow...
ええ 何とか　しかし…
However...
（鷹野）
“なぜ再発したか”ですの？
...why did she have a sudden relapse...?
What's more...
しかも またレベル５です
前回の入院は―
...it's Level 5 again.
The previous time she was hospitalized...
ご両親の事故死の現場にいたのが
沙都子ちゃんだけだったから―
...was because she was the only one present at the site of her parents' accidental death.
The stress of the subsequent investigation was the trigger for the symptoms to develop.
その取り調べのストレスが発症の
引き金になったのは分かるんですが
今は…
But now...
I believe...
（入江）
確か悟史君と一緒に叔母さん夫婦に
引き取られたはずですよ
...she was taken in by her aunt and uncle together with Satoshi-kun.
うん…　私も観察してみますわ
何が原因になっているのか
I'll keep an eye on her as well.
To find out the cause of this...
疲れているところ すみません
I'm sorry, you must be tired.
いいえ　全然
No, not at all.
Besides...
それに―
...if Satoko-chan spirals down into an unrecoverable state like this...
沙都子ちゃんが もしこのまま
回復不能な状態に陥ったら―
治療方法を確立するための
貴重な試料になるんですもの
...she'll become a valuable sample for our development of a treatment.
大切にしなくちゃ　アッハハハ…
We should handle her with care.
あ…　あんな子供を
解剖する気ですか？
You want to dissect a child like that?
ンフッ
ンッ…　そういうことにはしません
It won't happen.
I will make sure it won't come to that.
そうならないように してみせます
ンッフフ…
Manager.
（悟史）監督
沙都子の具合は どうですか？
How is Satoko doing?
It's been two weeks now...
もう２週間になるけど―
Is it still necessary for her to stay at the clinic?
まだ入院していたほうが
いいんでしょうか？
（入江）
経過は良好ですよ　ただ…
All is well so far.
Although...
...she said something that kinda bothered me.
ちょっと気になることを
言ってましてね
（沙都子）
私(わたくし)に灰皿を投げつけましたわ
He threw his ashtray at me.
He locked me out on the veranda.
私をベランダに出して
鍵をかけましたわ
He refused to give me lunch.
お昼ご飯も抜きにされましたわ
タバコの種類が違うと
言われましたわ
He yelled at me when I bought the wrong brand of cigarettes.
He slapped me in the face, saying I shouldn't be picky about food.
好き嫌いはダメだと
ほっぺを たたかれましたわ
カボチャを食べるまで
許さないって―
He said he wouldn't let me go until I ate all of my squashes...
イスにビニールひもで
縛られましたわ
...and tied me to the chair.
それから　それから…
And...
Did Satoko say all that...?
（悟史）そんなことを沙都子が…
Who is doing this to Satoko-chan?
（入江）一体 誰が
沙都子ちゃんに そんなことを？
Various people.
（悟史）いろいろな人です
（入江）え？
今までの父さんたち
Our fathers up until now.
But it wasn't just one person...
でも１人じゃなくて―
Satoko has probably lumped them all together in her mind.
たぶん全部 沙都子の中で
一緒くたに なってるんです
そうだったんですね
That's probably the case.
No...
いや…　私は てっきり
今のことかとばかり
I thought this was all going on right now.
大丈夫
Don't worry.
今は混乱しているのでしょうが
体が良くなれば きっと…
She's probably confused right now...
...but if her body improves, then...
（悟史）もし…
（入江）あ…
If...
もしご迷惑でなければ もう少し
入院させてもらえないでしょうか？
If it's not too much trouble...
...could you keep her at the clinic for a while longer?
実は沙都子 叔母さんたちとも
なじめてないんです
Thing is, Satoko isn't getting along very well with our aunt and uncle.
沙都子は
大人に あまり心を開かないので
Satoko doesn't open up to adults very much.
I think you're an outstanding older brother for always taking it up for her.
（入江）沙都子ちゃんを
かばってあげる悟史君は―
お兄さんのかがみだと思いますよ
今や沙都子ちゃんにとって
唯一の肉親は―
Satoko-chan might consider you the only family she has left now.
悟史君だけなのかも
しれませんからね
That's not it.
そんなんじゃないんです
I just felt that if Satoko would stay at the clinic for a little while longer...
沙都子が もうしばらく
入院してくれてたら―
...it would take a huge load off of my shoulders.
僕も その分
気が楽だなって思っただけです
退院してきたら
また叔母と もめると思います
If she comes home, she'll just end up fighting with Aunt again.
そしたら ケンカや怒鳴り声の
日々になって―
It'll be days of fighting and yelling again...
And whenever I think about getting dragged into it again...
僕もそれに
巻き込まれるのかなって思うと―
...I can't help but feel how great it would be if she could just stay at the clinic...
まだ入院していてくれたらって
そう思う僕がいて…
Satoshi-kun...
（入江）悟史君…
Everyone is going through painful times...
（羽入）みんな つらくなっていく
Everyone...
みんな　みんな
Just like back then...
それは あの時も…
あの時もボクが無力だったから
Back then...
...I was powerless as well.
[Opposed to the dam construction!]
（街宣車の男性）ダム建設 反対！
We're opposed to the dam construction!
ダム関係者は出ていけえ！
Those involved with the dam, get out!
[Those involved with the dam, get out now!]
ダム建設 反対！
We're opposed to the dam construction!
ダム関係者は出ていけえ！
Those involved with the dam, get out!
（鷹野）失礼します　所長
Excuse me, Director.
The remaining test results came in from Tokyo just now.
先ほど東京から 残りの
検査結果が郵送されてきました
Irie Clinic
Kyousuke Irie
それは それは！　ンッ…
Well, well...
Hinamizawa Syndrome
Test Result
（入江）ハア…
So nothing was found?
やはりダメでしたの？
（入江）
雛見沢症候群という寄生虫感染症が
ほぼ間違いなく存在するという―
We have enough data to all but prove the existence of parasites as the cause of Hinamizawa Syndrome...
浮かし彫りの情報は
いくらでも集まるのに―
原因となる病原体が
発見できないのでは…
...yet we can't find the microbe in question...
Hinamizawa Syndrome
Test Result
I had hoped we would be able to find them easily using an electron microscope...
（鷹野）電子顕微鏡を使えば―
あっさり見つかるだろうと
期待していたのですけど
Then that means...
となると 極小の極小なのか―
...that either they are atomically small...
...or there is some problem with our specimen.
あるいは検体そのものに
問題があるのかもしれません
What do you mean by that?
と申しますと？
For instance...
（入江）例えばですが
ネズミの死体を調べたところで―
One would be unable to find fleas on a dead mouse.
ノミを見つけることはできません
宿主が死んだ時点で 寄生虫である
ノミの生活基盤が崩壊するからです
This is because with the host's death, the parasites' habitat collapses as well.
So that means...
ということは―
生きているうちに調べればいい
ということになりますかしら？
...we should just examine while our specimen is still alive, right?
分かりました　用意させましょう
Understood.
I will arrange one.
B-But...
し…　しかし人権があります
What about human rights?
生きてるうちに
その脳を調べるなんて…
We can't just poke at someone's brain while they are alive!?
All it amounts to is putting a terminal patient to sleep a little while earlier.
いずれ亡くなる方に―
ほんの少し早く お休みいただく
というだけの話ですわ
On paper, of course.
書類上はね
Hello?
Okonogi-san?
（鷹野）小此木(おこのぎ)さん
I have a request for you.
（鷹野）お願いしたいことが
あるんですけど…
No way...
（入江）そんな…
そんなことが―
We can't just do this...?
許されるはずが…
（鷹野）ええ　そう
Yes.
お願いできるかしら？
Can I count on you?
（富竹(とみたけ)）ごめんよ　鷹野さん
僕が散歩に誘ったりしなきゃ…
Sorry, Takano-san.
If I hadn't invited you for a walk...
気にしないで　ジロウさん
That's alright, Jirou-san.
土砂降りになるかもしれないことを
覚悟の上で出かけたんだから
I came along knowing that it might start pouring along the way.
それとも私と一緒じゃ
気分転換にならないかしら？
Or could it be...
...that you can't relax with me around?
（富竹）あ…　そんなことないよ
T-That's not true!
Come to think of it...
（鷹野）そういえば―
こうしてジロウさんと２人きりで
ゆっくり おしゃべりするのは―
...this is the first time we've been able to talk alone like this.
初めてね
Y-You're right...
あそっ…　そうだね
いつも所長とか
他の研究員の人がいたりするから…
Normally, the Director and other researchers are around.
ねえ カメラって面白い？
Hey...
Is it fun to take pictures?
（鷹野）
どうやって撮れば いいのかしら？
How do you do it?
あ…　こうして見て
ピントを合わせて…
Look through it like this...
...then focus...
（鷹野）フッ…　こう？
Like this?
あ…　ハア…
Hey...
（鷹野）
ねえ　それから どうするの？
What do I do after that?
（作業員）ヌウハハッ！　ウウッ
（現場監督）ウエエッ
（羽入）
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni
Kai
This is bad...
（作業員）ヤベえ　ヤベえよ！
This is bad!
Manager...
（作業員）
監督　返事してくださいよ
Say something!
Manager!
（作業員）監督ー！
（作業員）あ…　あほんだら
死んでるに決まってんだろうがあ
Dumbass...
Can't you see he's dead!?
M-Manager...!
（作業員）か…　監督…
（作業員）仕方ねえじゃねえか
We couldn't help it!
正当防衛だろ　正当防衛！
It was self-defense!
Self-defense!
（作業員）カー！　うっ うめえ
Delicious!
A nice beer after work is the best!
（作業員）やっぱ
仕事終わりのビールは最高だな
But...
（作業員）
だけど監督に見つかったら…
...if Manager finds out...
It's fine.
（作業員）平気だよ　こう毎日
反対派の妨害に遭っちゃよ
We're being harrassed by the anti-dam faction every day.
We have the right to drink some beer to make up for it.
ビールぐらい飲まなきゃ
やってらんないだろうがあ
ンッンッ…　クー！　うめえ
Great!
（現場監督）ンン…
（作業員）監督？
Manager?
（現場監督）ンン…　エエイ！
（一同）うわあ！
え…　かっ 監督!?
（現場監督）ハアッ
M-Manager!?
ギエアア！
You guys saw it too, didn't you?
（作業員）
お前らだって見てただろうが
ハアッ…
That was no human.
（作業員）あんなの人間じゃねえ
It was a demon!
鬼だ
Quit fucking crying!
いつまでもナヨナヨしてんじゃねえ
やっちまったもんは仕方ねえだろ
Nothing we can do about it anymore!
You aren't thinking of turning yourself in, are you?
まさか自首しようなんて
思ってんじゃねえだろうな
I ain't going to jail for this!
ムショなんて冗談じゃねえ
I ain't going back there ever again!
あんなとこ
二度と戻ってたまるか！
All we can do now is hide the body and act like we know nothing!
こうなったら―
こいつの死体を隠して
すっとぼけるしかねえんだ！
B-But...
（作業員）でっ でも死体なんか
隠したってバレるよ　いずれ…
Even if we hide the body, we'll be found out eventually!
Besides, if we just plead self-defense...
それより正当防衛だってことを
ちゃんと主張して…
（作業員）テイッ
（作業員）アアッ…
Don't be such a pussy!
甘ったれたこと言ってんじゃねえ
Look at how much of a mess we made out of him!
これだけズタボロに
やっちまったんだぞ！
His parents wouldn't even be able to identify him anymore!
親だって見分け
つかねえぐらいによお
Fuck self-defense...
正当防衛どころか
過剰防衛でも済まねえんだよお…
We can't justify this shit!
Listen up.
いいか　俺たちゃ殺人犯なんだ
殺人犯！
We are murderers.
Murderers!
If we don't do something, it's ten to twenty years in the slammer!
グズグズ言ってりゃ
10年 20年食らっちまうんだよ
Fuck this...
冗談じゃねえ　捕まってたまるか
I ain't getting caught...
ヒヒヒ…　いいこと思いついた
I just had a great idea...
What?
（作業員）何を…
（作業員）ヒヒッ…
This bastard's corpse...
この野郎の死体をな
みんなで仲良く割り算すんだよ
We're gonna divide it equally like the good friends we are.
So you bastards won't be able to rat out the rest of us.
裏切り者を出さないためにな
Everyone will be responsible for hiding their own piece.
バラしたものは
各自が責任を持って隠すんだ
（悲鳴）
（作業員）なあ？
See?
This way, we're all in this together.
これなら全員 仲良く共犯だろう
ンッ　ヘヘッ…　ゲヘヘ…
ゲヘヘ…　ヘヘヘ…
Is it true a patient in his terminal stages has turned up!?
末期患者が出たというのは
本当ですか!?
Let me go!
放せ！　放せえ！
Let me go!!!
I ain't getting caught!
捕まってたまるか！　あいつらだな
あいつらが裏切りやがったんだな！
It was them, huh!?
They betrayed me!
チクショオー！
Fucking shit!
Let's put him to sleep for now.
とにかく麻酔で眠らせましょう
（叫び声）
He might end up biting his tongue like this!
（入江）このままでは自分の舌を
かんでしまうかもしれない
ハア…　もう少し
観察したかったのですけれど
I wanted to observe him for a little while longer, but...
Guess I have no choice.
仕方ありませんわね
（作業員）放せ！　ウア…
Who on earth is that man?
（入江）一体 あの男は何者です？
Where did you capture him from?
どこから連れてきたんです？
Don't put it like that.
（鷹野）人聞きが悪いですわねえ
I encountered him by chance on my way home from the clinic.
診療所からの帰り道
偶然に遭遇しただけですわ
フッフフ…
But with just that...
しかし それだけでは
検査できても…
Even after an examination...
Care to guess what that man was carrying with him?
あの男 何を持っていたと
思います？
うっ　これは…
What's this!?
ンッフフフ…　どう見ても―
No matter how you look at it...
...it seems to be a right arm.
右手に見えますわ　それも人間の
A human one, at that.
Plus, it doesn't seem to have been chopped off that long ago.
しかも切り取って
まだ時間が浅いようですし
In other words...
つまり あの男は近隣で起こった
何らかの死体遺棄事件の犯人…
...that man is the culprit of some corpse disposal incident that happened nearby...?
ということですか
Oh?
あらあ　殺人犯そのものとは
思わないんですの？　ンッフフフ
You don't actually think the man is the murderer himself?
Jirou-san.
ジロウさん　どう？
何か分かった？
Did you find out anything?
[Background Check Report]
ふうん　あの男
前科者で しかも執行猶予中なのね
That man...
...seems to be an ex-convict, currently on probation.
You shouldn't have any qualms about dissecting the scum of society, right, Director Irie?
こんな社会のクズが相手なら―
入江所長も
解剖に躊躇(ちゅうちょ)はないのでは？
Did he perpetrate the crime?
彼が事件を起こしたのか―
Or did this disease he was infected with instigate it?
彼のかかった この病気が
事件を起こさせたのか―
分かりませんよ
We don't know that.
Still...
しかし レベル５です
治療の余地はないかと
...he's Level 5.
He has no way of recovering.
What will you do?
どうなさいます？
Takano-san, please make arrangements with Tokyo.
（入江）鷹野さんには
東京との調整をお願いします
Roger that.
了解しましたわ
We finally got our hands on a fresh specimen.
ようやく手に入った
生きのいい検体ですもの
It would be such a waste to stop at just peeking inside his brain.
ただ脳をのぞくだけじゃ
もったいないですわ
フッハハハ…
（ドアが開く音）
（大石(おおいし)）ンン…
（検視官）お前さん―
You should go back upstairs.
少し上に戻ったほうがいいぞ
The air here is difficult to handle for those not used to it.
ここの空気は
慣れん奴には少々きつい
No...
（大石）いや…
You used to be feared by every street punk around...
（検視官）
チンピラもよけて通るお前に
げんこつ食らわせたのは―
He was the only one who ever dared to throw a punch at you.
後にも先にも こいつだけだったな
（大石）ンッ…
（現場監督）バカ野郎！
Fuckin' moron!
And you call yourself a man of Japan!?
（現場監督）
おめえ それでも日本男児か!?
I think he beat me more than my real father.
ほんとの親父より
げんこつをもらった気がします
Do you have a suspect?
（検視官）
ホシの目星は付いとるのか？
I don't have proof, but...
証拠はありませんが―
...I'm sure the Sonozaki family, who heavily fueled the flames of the dam war, is involved somehow.
ダム戦争をあおるだけ あおった
園崎の家が絡んでいることは―
間違いないと にらんでいます
The Sonozakis of the three great houses, huh...
御三家の園崎か
こりゃあ難儀なヤマだよ
That's a steep hill to climb.
I will make them pay for this.
きっちり
けじめは つけますよ
I will retrieve the old man's right arm as well.
おやっさんの右腕も
取り返してみせます
Everything twists into a crooked state of affairs...
（羽入）
すべては妙な具合にねじれ―
...and many people are getting dragged into it.
さまざまな人々が巻き込まれていく
I can only watch from the side.
ボクはそれを ただ見つめるだけ
I'm sorry...
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
What's wrong?
どうしました？
I just heard someone say "I'm sorry."
（沙都子）“ごめんなさい”って
声がしましたの
An apologetic voice...
謝る声が
Are these happenings all the result of Takano's will?
（羽入）
それは すべて鷹野の意志の
なせる業なのでしょうか？
And do I really not have the power to stop it?
そしてボクには それを止める力は
ないのでしょうか？
Cast
Hanyuu
Satoko Houjou
Rika Furude
Satoshi Houjou
Mion Sonozaki
Jirou Tomitake
Miyo Takano
Kuraudo Ooishi
Kyousuke Irie
Yui Horie
Mika Kanai
Yukari Tamura
Yuu Kobayashi
Satsuki Yukino
Tohru Ookawa
Miki Itou
Chafuurin
Toshihiko Seki
anata no nakigara ni tsuchi wo kakeru
I cover your corpse with soil...
Cast
Oryou
Satoko's Father
Forensic Officer
Villagers
Shizuka Okohira
Masami Iwasaki
Eiji Maruyama
Daisuke Matsuoka
Hiroki Yasumoto
Daisuke Sasaki
Cast
Villagers
Government Officials
Dam Foreman
Laborer
Nobuyuki Kobushi
Hiroomi Sugino
Tsutomu Densaka
Gen Nakano
Satoshi Tsuruoka
Katsuhiro Oota
sore ga kinjirareteita toshitemo
...even though that may have been forbidden.
junsui na manazashi no kairaku ni wa
There was a temptation you could not hide...
kakushikirenai yuuwaku ga atta
...in your pure, blissful eyes.
doushite tsumi ga aru no darou
Why does sin exist?
Ending Theme
"Taishou a"
(Target a)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition/
Arrangement
doushite batsu ga aru no darou
Why does punishment exist?
hone no saki wa amari ni mo shiroku
That blindingly white tip of the bone...
mugen ni tsuzuku yami wo sasotta
...invited the infinite darkness.
Scenario
Rika Nakase
Storyboards
Episode Direction
Ryo Yasumura
Yuuki Onoda
nani mo kamo ga azayaka ni miete
I can see everything clearly now.
Animation Supervisor
Minefumi Harada
sugu ni kieteshimau
It will soon vanish.
Animation Production
Studio Deen
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
© 2007 Ryukishi07/Hinamizawa Three Great Houses
Whenever I go shopping, I often get candy as a reward...
（梨花(りか)）
ボクは お買い物に行っても
よく お駄賃にアメをもらいますが
...but Satoko never gets any, even if she's with me.
（梨花）沙都子は
一緒に行っても もらえませんです
Also...
それにボクも…
Wasn't that candy given to you?
そのアメは 梨花がもらった物では
ありませんの？
The person who gave it to you wanted you to eat it.
渡した人だって―
梨花に食べてほしいと思って
渡したんですわ
So it would be rude for me to take it.
だから私が食べたら失礼ですわよ
...I did something horrible to her.
（梨花）
ひどいことを してしまったのです
Mii, we're friends with Satoko and Satoshi, right?
魅(み)ぃ　ボクたちは
沙都子や悟史の仲間なのですよね？
Of course.
（魅音(みおん)）
そうだよ　２人とも大事な仲間だよ
They're good friends of us.
Then can't we do anything to save our friends?
なら ボクたちの仲間を
救うために―
何か できることは
ないのでしょうか？
I wonder...
あたしたちに
何ができるんだろうね？
...if there's anything we can do...
If an ally for Satoko were ever to show up...
（魅音）もし沙都子に味方が
現れてくれるとしたら それは―
...it would have to be someone without ties of obligation to the village.
村のしがらみに とらわれない
そういう人なんだろうね
Rika-chan?
（魅音）梨花ちゃん？
I'm sure...
（梨花）きっと…
（魅音）え？
I'm sure someone from outside who isn't bound by the village rules will come.
きっと村の外から しがらみに
とらわれない人が やってきます
I'm sure he'll come.
来ます　きっと
If we combine our strength with his...
“彼”と力を合わせて ボクたちは
村の悪弊を打ち破るのです
...we'll be able to shatter the evils of the village.
That will be the first key to opening up our future.
それがボクたちの未来を開く
最初のカギ
え…　何それ？　何かの小説？
What are you talking about?
Is that from some kind of book?
No.
違うのですよ
You will understand eventually.
そのうち分かる時が来るのです
That will be the true beginning.
（梨花）その時が本当の始まり
And it will lead everything to an end.
そして すべての終わりになる
Isn't that right, Hanyuu?
そうでしょ？　羽入
Yes.
はい
I will fight.
ボクは頑張るのです
This time...
今度こそ―
...carrying the power of belief.
“信じる”その力をもって
（羽入）久々の
“教えて 黒梨花”コーナー！
It's another long-awaited "Tell me, Dark Rika" corner!
相談者は雛見沢村の
北条鉄平(てっぺい)さんなのです
Today's caller is Mr. Teppei Houjou from Hinamizawa!
（梨花）今日は どんな質問？
What question do you have today?
（羽入）“以前から
疑問に思っていたことですが”
"This has puzzled me for some time...
“梨花が辛い物を食べたり
お酒を飲むと―”
Whenever Rika eats something spicy, or drinks alcohol...
“羽入が辛かったり
酔っ払ったりするみたいですが”
...it seems Hanyuu's mouth is on fire, or she gets drunk.
“その辺の２人の関係は
どうなっているんですか？”
How does this connection between you two work exactly?
“さっぱり分かりません
教えてください”なのです
I have no idea.
Please tell me." he asks.
（梨花）お答えします
余計な お世話よ！
Here is your answer.
None of your damn business!
（羽入）はうあう～！
Next time, the Festival Accompanying Chapter, Part Four.
次回　祭囃し編 其の四
「謀略」
"Plot."
見るのです～
Please watch!
On a side note, Hanyuu ***** as well.
（梨花）ちなみに…
…も羽入がしているのよ
（羽入）はにゅうう～ん…
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
Next time
Festival Accompanying Chapter
Part Four
Plot